urionlinejudge.com.br 2019-12-14

# Privacy Policy - URI Online Judge

Learn more about our privacy policy.

* ### Privacy Policy

This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their 'Personally Identifiable Information' (PII) is being used online. PII is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website. 

* ### Personal Information

#### What personal information do we collect from the people that visit our website?

When registering on our site, you may be asked to enter your name, username, email address, or other details to help you with your experience. Upon registering or connecting using a social network, we collect the information you authorized the provider to share. That data is used to correctly authenticate you. 

When you submit a solution to a problem in our repository or in contests hosted at our platform, the source-code is stored in our servers. It will remain there until you delete your account. 

We also collect data you provide us using any formularies. These may contain data or information you agree to share with us. 

#### When do we collect information?

We collect information from you when you register on our site, subscribe to a newsletter, respond to a survey, fill out a form, send a feedback, open a support ticket, or enter information on our site. 

#### How can I edit my URI Online Judge data?

You can update your data at any time from your profile page here. 

#### How do we use your information?

We may use the information we collect from you when you register, sign up for our newsletter, respond to a survey or marketing communication, surf the website, or use certain other site features in the following ways: 

  * To personalize your experience and to allow us to deliver the type of content in which you are most interested;
  * To improve our website in order to better serve you;
  * To allow us to better service you in responding to your customer service requests;
  * To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature;
  * To ask for ratings and reviews of services or product;
  * To follow up with them after correspondence (live chat or email).

* ### Automatically Collected Data

#### Does URI Online Judge automatically collects data?

Yes. We automatically collect usage information when you visit our website or use our services. We may send one or more cookies to your computer or device that uniquely identifies your browser and lets us help enhance your navigation and improve your experience. Further details about Cookie usage is described in our Cookies page. You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser settings. Since browsers are a little different, look at your browser's help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies. If you turn cookies off it will turn off some of the features of the site. 

#### Does URI Online Judge uses tracking services such as Google Analytics?

We also collect analytics data and use third-party analytics tools, to help us measure traffic and usage trends for the service. These tools collect information sent by your browser or mobile device, including the pages you visit, your use of third-party applications, and other information that assists us in analyzing and improving the service. 

#### Does URI Online Judge keep logs of user interaction?

Yes. URI Online Judge collects log file information from your browser or mobile device each time you access or use our services. Log file information may include information such as your web request, IP address, browser type, information about your mobile device, referring/exit pages and URLs, the number of clicks and how you interact with links on the service, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed, and other such information. 

#### Does URI Online Judge tracks emails?

Yes. We use clear gifs in HTML-based emails sent to our users to track which emails are opened and which links are clicked. The information allows for more accurate reporting and improvement of the service. 

* ### Data Protection

#### How do we protect your information?

Our website is scanned on a regular basis for security holes and known vulnerabilities in order to make your visit to our site as safe as possible. We use regular Malware Scanning. 

Your personal information is contained behind secured networks and is only accessible by a limited number of persons who have special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential. In addition, all sensitive information you supply is encrypted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology. 

We implement a variety of security measures when a user enters, submits, or accesses their information to maintain the safety of your personal information. 

* ### Data Storage

#### Where does URI Online Judge store your data?

Our services are hosted in the Digital Ocean cloud. By default, URI Online Judge hosts in the New York (US) regions. The data we collect is stored on those servers located in the United States. 

As URI Online Judge is made in Brazil, a backup copy of all the data we collect from our website and the source-codes you submitted are also stored in our on-site server. 

#### How long does URI Online Judge retain data?

URI Online Judge maintains all collected data until we mark users as non-active or a user deletes their own account. Users can delete their own accounts and data here. However, not all the information is deleted from our services and backups. A complete list of what is and what is not removed is available on the "Delete Account" page and also is described in our Terms of Service. 

* ### Data Usage

#### What my data used for?

The data we collect is used to correctly identify you when you authenticate and use our services (to identify your submissions, publications, and actions on the platform). We also use this data to customize and enhance your experience when using our services. The URI Online Judge understands that you use our platform to improve your programming skills. Therefore, we perform some analyzes to report your current state of evolution and also assist you in your progress. 

#### Is my data used for communication purposes?

Yes. We may use your basic user contact information to communicate with you about product and security updates, relevant marketing, training, and events. URI Online Judge users may opt-out of these communications at any time by updating the account's settings, or by clicking on the unsubscribe link in the emails. 

#### Is my data used for research purposes?

Yes. We may use your anonymized data, progress, and statistics for research purposes and technical reports. We may also use the same data to develop new features and services or to improve our existing ones. We also collect and use the information you provide us by completing our surveys and questionnaires. 

Your anonymized data may also be shared with research groups partners that work in collaboration with our team to research and develop new technologies and features to improve your experience using our services. However, the data is only shared with research groups after a confidential agreement is signed by the lead research and all those researchers how are involved in the project. 

* ### Third Party

#### Does URI Online Judge discloses the collected data?

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your Personally Identifiable Information unless we provide users with advance notice. This does not include website hosting partners and other parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or serving our users, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release information when it's release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others' rights, property or safety. 

Non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses. 

#### Does URI Online Judge share my data in an API?

URI Online Judge can transfer some of the collected information via our API, to pre-approved applications only if you have confirmed and authorized the third party application to have access to that information. The information is shared on an application basis and it is detailed in the authorization screen. You can revoke this sharing at any time. However, we are not responsible for the information stored by the third party. Hence, you must request directly to the application you have previously granted access to delete your data. 

* ### Confidentiality

The team that maintains the URI Online Judge services will keep confidential all source-codes submitted for automatic correction, not transferring them to third parties. The only exception to this rule is if you authorize a professor when using the URI Online Academic module to visualize your solutions to the problems that compose the lists of exercises you were invited and agreed to participate. 

* ### Updates to Privacy Policy

In case you chose to continue using our services, you will be subject to the updates we made to this document. Such updates can be made at any time. Therefore, we encourage you to check this page regularly. 

#### When our Policy was last updated?

The URI Online Judge Privacy Policy was last edited on June 2nd, 2018.
